<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<articulos xmlns="uo239795" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
           xsi:schemaLocation="uo239795 tarea4.xsd">
    <articulo>
        <titulo>
            Midgar: Detection of people through computer vision in the Internet of Things scenarios to improve the
            security in Smart Cities, Smart Towns, and Smart Homes.
        </titulo>
        <autores>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Cristian González García</nombreAutor>
                <correo>gonzalezgarciacristian@hotmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Daniel Meana-Llorián</nombreAutor>
                <correo>danielmeanallorian@gmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>B. Cristina Pelayo García-Bustelo</nombreAutor>
                <correo>crispelayo@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Juan Manuel Cueva Lovelle</nombreAutor>
                <correo>cueva@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Néstor García-Fernández</nombreAutor>
                <correo>nestor@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
        </autores>
        <resumen>Could we use Computer Vision in the Internet of Things for using pictures as sensors? This is the
            principal hypothesis that we want to resolve. Currently, in order to create safety areas, cities, or homes,
            people use IP cameras. Nevertheless, this system needs people who watch the camera images, watch the
            recording after something occurred, or watch when the camera notifies them of any movement. These are the
            disadvantages. Furthermore, there are many Smart Cities and Smart Homes around the world. This is why we
            thought of using the idea of the Internet of Things to add a way of automating the use of IP cameras. In our
            case, we propose the analysis of pictures through Computer Vision to detect people in the analysed pictures.
            With this analysis, we are able to obtain if these pictures contain people and handle the pictures as if
            they were sensors with two possible states. Notwithstanding, Computer Vision is a very complicated field.
            This is why we needed a second hypothesis: Could we work with Computer Vision in the Internet of Things with
            a good accuracy to automate or semi-automate this kind of events? The demonstration of these hypotheses
            required a testing over our Computer Vision module to check the possibilities that we have to use this
            module in a possible real environment with a good accuracy. Our proposal, as a possible solution, is the
            analysis of entire sequence instead of isolated pictures for using pictures as sensors in the Internet of
            Things.
        </resumen>
        <claves>
            <clave>Smart Cities</clave>
            <clave>Smart Towns</clave>
            <clave>Smart Homes</clave>
            <clave>Internet of Things</clave>
            <clave>Smart Objects</clave>
            <clave>Computer Vision</clave>
            <clave>Surveillance</clave>
            <clave>Security</clave>
        </claves>
        <revista>Future Generation Comp. Syst</revista>
        <enumeracionRevista>
            <volumenRevista>76</volumenRevista>
        </enumeracionRevista>
        <paginaInicio>275</paginaInicio>
        <paginaFinal>284</paginaFinal>
        <año>2017</año>
    </articulo>
    <articulo>
        <titulo>A review about Smart Objects, Sensors, and Actuators.</titulo>
        <autores>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Cristian González García</nombreAutor>
                <correo>gonzalezgarciacristian@hotmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Daniel Meana-Llorián</nombreAutor>
                <correo>danielmeanallorian@gmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>B. Cristina Pelayo García-Bustelo</nombreAutor>
                <correo>crispelayo@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Juan Manuel Cueva Lovelle</nombreAutor>
                <correo>cueva@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Néstor García-Fernández</nombreAutor>
                <correo>nestor@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
        </autores>
        <resumen>Smart Objects and the Internet of Things are two ideas which describe the future, walk together, and
            complement each other. Thus, the interconnection among objects can make them more intelligent or expand
            their intelligence to unsuspected limits. This could be achieved with a new network that interconnects each
            object around the world. However, to achieve this goal, the objects need a network that supports
            heterogeneous and ubiquitous objects, a network where exists more traffic among objects than among humans,
            but supporting for both types. For these reasons, both concepts are very close. Cities, houses, cars,
            machines, or any another object that can sense, respond, work, or make easier the lives of their owner. This
            is a part of the future, an immediate future. Notwithstanding, first of all, there are to resolve a series
            of problems. The most important problem is the heterogeneity of objects. This article is going to show a
            theoretical frame and the related work about Smart Object. The article will explain what are Smart Objects,
            doing emphasis in their difference with Not- Smart Objects. After, we will present one of the different
            object classification system, in our opinion, the most complete.
        </resumen>
        <claves>
            <clave>Actuator</clave>
            <clave>Internet of things</clave>
            <clave>Sensor</clave>
            <clave>SmartCities</clave>
        </claves>
        <revista>IJIMAI</revista>
        <enumeracionRevista>
            <numeroRevista>4</numeroRevista>
        </enumeracionRevista>
        <paginaInicio>7</paginaInicio>
        <paginaFinal>10</paginaFinal>
        <año>2017</año>
    </articulo>
    <articulo>
        <titulo>SenseQ: Replying questions of Social Networks users by using a Wireless Sensor Network based on sensor
            relationships
        </titulo>
        <autores>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Cristian González García</nombreAutor>
                <correo>gonzalezgarciacristian@hotmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Daniel Meana-Llorián</nombreAutor>
                <correo>danielmeanallorian@gmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>B. Cristina Pelayo García-Bustelo</nombreAutor>
                <correo>crispelayo@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Vicente García Díaz</nombreAutor>
                <correo>garciavicente@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Néstor García-Fernández</nombreAutor>
                <correo>nestor@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
        </autores>
        <resumen>Social Networks are a way of establishing communications with friends or family and a way of knowing
            what happens around us. However, there are not machines that provide users with information about their
            worries. What happens if a user wants to know if it is raining in a specific place at that moment? He needs
            to ask a person who is in that place at that moment. Why not take advantage of the Internet of Things to
            collect information in real time and answer users questions? The Internet of Things is a field that tries to
            measure everything by gathering data from sensors and interconnect different objects. Why not combine Social
            Networks and the Internet of Things? In this paper, we propose the development of a new system that will
            allow users to ask for information to a network of sensors through Social Networks, concretely in this case
            through Twitter. The system will have sensors registered by different users and this system that will be
            used to answer questions of other users. The system will be able to collect information of users sensors,
            process it, and use it to answer users questions through Social Networks. In order to gather the data from
            sensors and combine them, we propose three dierent types of relationships between sensors: neighboring
            relationship, familiar relationship and working relationship. Besides, we propose an architecture based on
            three layers: social layer, backend layer and object layer.
        </resumen>
        <claves>
            <clave>Social Networks</clave>
            <clave>Sensors</clave>
            <clave>The Internet of Things</clave>
            <clave>Twitter</clave>
            <clave>WSN</clave>
        </claves>
        <revista>ACM</revista>
        <enumeracionRevista>
            <numeroRevista>8</numeroRevista>
        </enumeracionRevista>
        <paginaInicio>1</paginaInicio>
        <paginaFinal>23</paginaFinal>
        <año>2016</año>
    </articulo>
    <articulo>
        <titulo>Swift vs. Objective-C: A New Programming Language</titulo>
        <autores>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Cristian González García</nombreAutor>
                <correo>gonzalezgarciacristian@hotmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Daniel Meana-Llorián</nombreAutor>
                <correo>danielmeanallorian@gmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>B. Cristina Pelayo García-Bustelo</nombreAutor>
                <correo>crispelayo@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Juan Manuel Cueva Lovelle</nombreAutor>
                <correo>cueva@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Jordán Pascual Espada</nombreAutor>
                <correo>pascualjordan@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
        </autores>
        <resumen>The appearance of a new programming language gives the necessity to contrast its contribution with the
            existing programming languages to evaluate the novelties and improvements that the new programming language
            offers for developers. These kind of studies can show us the efficiency, improvements and useful or
            uselessness of the new programming languages. Also these studies can show us the good or bad properties of
            the existing programming languages. For these reasons, these studies allow us to know if the new programming
            language is offering improvements or relapses. In this article, we compare the new programming language of
            Apple, Swift, with the main programming language of Apple before Swift, Objective-C. We are going to show
            the differences, characteristics and novelties to verify the words of Apple about Swift. With that we want
            to answer the next question: Is Swift a new programming language easier, more secure and quicker to develop
            than Objective-C?
        </resumen>
        <claves>
            <clave>Object oriented programming</clave>
            <clave>Programming</clave>
            <clave>Functional programming</clave>
            <clave>Programming profession</clave>
            <clave>Software</clave>
        </claves>
        <revista>International Journal of Interactive Multimedia and Artificial Intelligence</revista>
        <enumeracionRevista>
            <numeroRevista>3</numeroRevista>
            <volumenRevista>3</volumenRevista>
        </enumeracionRevista>
        <paginaInicio>74</paginaInicio>
        <paginaFinal>81</paginaFinal>
        <año>2016</año>
    </articulo>
    <articulo>
        <titulo>Using Model-Driven Architecture Principles to Generate Applications based on Interconnecting Smart
            Objects and Sensors
        </titulo>
        <autores>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Cristian González García</nombreAutor>
                <correo>gonzalezgarciacristian@hotmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Jordán Pascual Espada</nombreAutor>
                <correo>pascualjordan@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
        </autores>
        <resumen>There has been a rise in the quantity of Smart Things present in our daily life:
            Smartphones, smart TVs, sensor networks, smart appliances, and many other home and
            industry automation devices. The disadvantage is that each one is similar but very different
            from the others because they use different kinds of connections, different protocols, different
            hardware, and different operative systems; even if they belong to a similar kind, and
            depending on the manufacturer, two Smartphones or two humidity sensors can be totally ...
        </resumen>
        <claves>
            <clave>Sensors</clave>
        </claves>
        <revista>Advances and Applications in Model-Driven Engineering</revista>
        <enumeracionRevista>
            <numeroRevista>8</numeroRevista>
        </enumeracionRevista>
        <paginaInicio>73</paginaInicio>
        <paginaFinal>87</paginaFinal>
        <año>2013</año>
    </articulo>
    <articulo>
        <titulo>MUSPEL: Generation of Applications to Interconnect Heterogeneous Objects Using Model-Driven
            Engineering
        </titulo>
        <autores>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Cristian González García</nombreAutor>
                <correo>gonzalezgarciacristian@hotmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Jordán Pascual Espada</nombreAutor>
                <correo>pascualjordan@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
        </autores>
        <resumen>Internet of Things (IoT) is a paradigm that promotes a world in which smart objects and electronic
            devices communicate and coordinate autonomously to perform a wide range of tasks. From a technical point of
            view, the development of IoT systems is not an easy task; due to the great heterogeneity among smart objects
            and the large number of technologies applied, the developers of these systems must have strong technical
            knowledge. In this chapter, the authors use the eclipse modelling framework to define a domain-specific
            language that allows specifying the coordination and communication between different types of smart objects,
            regardless of the smart object technical characteristics. The proposed domain specific language has been
            designed to be used in an intuitive and easy way for people without technical knowledge. This solution aims
            to be useful in many areas and to achieve constant adaptation and evolution of IoT systems.
        </resumen>
        <claves>
            <clave>Model-Driven</clave>
        </claves>
        <revista>Handbook of Research on Innovations in Systems and Software Engineering</revista>
        <enumeracionRevista>
            <numeroRevista>8</numeroRevista>
        </enumeracionRevista>
        <paginaInicio>365</paginaInicio>
        <paginaFinal>368</paginaFinal>
        <año>2014</año>
    </articulo>
    <articulo>
        <titulo>Midgar: Generation of heterogeneous objects interconnecting applications. A Domain Specific Language
            proposal for Internet of Things scenarios
        </titulo>
        <autores>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Cristian González García</nombreAutor>
                <correo>gonzalezgarciacristian@hotmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>B. Cristina Pelayo García-Bustelo</nombreAutor>
                <correo>crispelayo@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>GuillermoCueva-Fernandez</nombreAutor>
                <correo>cuevafdz@gmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Jordán Pascual Espada</nombreAutor>
                <correo>pascualjordan@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
        </autores>
        <claves>
            <clave>Internet of Things</clave>
            <clave>Ubiquitous computing</clave>
            <clave>Sensor network</clave>
            <clave>Model Driven Engineering</clave>
            <clave>Domain Specific Language</clave>
            <clave>Smart Objects</clave>
        </claves>
        <revista>Computer Networks</revista>
        <enumeracionRevista>
            <volumenRevista>64</volumenRevista>
        </enumeracionRevista>
        <paginaInicio>143</paginaInicio>
        <paginaFinal>158</paginaFinal>
        <año>2014</año>
    </articulo>
    <articulo>
        <titulo>Vitruvius: An expert system for vehicle sensor tracking and managing application generation</titulo>
        <autores>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Cristian González García</nombreAutor>
                <correo>gonzalezgarciacristian@hotmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Néstor García-Fernández</nombreAutor>
                <correo>nestor@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>GuillermoCueva-Fernandez</nombreAutor>
                <correo>cuevafdz@gmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Jordán Pascual Espada</nombreAutor>
                <correo>pascualjordan@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Juan Manuel Cueva Lovelle</nombreAutor>
                <correo>cueva@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
        </autores>
        <resumen>Internet of Things promotes the use of physical intelligent connecting objects to automatize processes
            and tasks in multiple areas of society. There are numerous intelligent objects with different sensors and
            communication mechanisms. Today, road vehicles contain many advanced sensors that allow the collection of
            great amounts of parameters. With an appropriate communication mechanism, vehicles can be converted to
            intelligent objects capable of forming very useful systems such as road security, vehicle maintenance, urban
            mobility, traffic congestion, fleet management, CO2 emissions, etc. The problem is that the implementation
            of a system is not quick or easy. Many subsystems and heterogeneous elements intervene. The lack of speed in
            the development can be a big inconvenient, especially when the environment is as dynamic as traffic, subject
            to many variables. Currently, there are several platforms that integrate intelligent objects and the
            generation of applications, but none of them are focused on road vehicles. In this paper we present
            Vitruvius, a platform where users with no programming knowledge can design and quickly implement rich web
            applications based on the data consumption in real time from interconnected vehicles and sensors.
        </resumen>
        <claves>
            <clave>Internet of Things</clave>
            <clave>Vehicle sensor</clave>
            <clave>Application generation</clave>
            <clave>Web application</clave>
            <clave>Tracking</clave>
            <clave>Domain-specific language</clave>
        </claves>
        <revista>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</revista>
        <enumeracionRevista>
            <volumenRevista>42</volumenRevista>
        </enumeracionRevista>
        <paginaInicio>178</paginaInicio>
        <paginaFinal>188</paginaFinal>
        <año>2014</año>
    </articulo>
    <articulo>
        <titulo>IoFClime: The fuzzy logic and the Internet of Things to control indoor temperature regarding the outdoor
            ambient conditions
        </titulo>
        <autores>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Cristian González García</nombreAutor>
                <correo>gonzalezgarciacristian@hotmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Daniel Meana-Llorián</nombreAutor>
                <correo>danielmeanallorian@gmail.com</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>B. Cristina Pelayo García-Bustelo</nombreAutor>
                <correo>crispelayo@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Juan Manuel Cueva Lovelle</nombreAutor>
                <correo>cueva@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
            <autor>
                <nombreAutor>Néstor García-Fernández</nombreAutor>
                <correo>nestor@uniovi.es</correo>
            </autor>
        </autores>
        <claves>
            <clave>Internet of Things</clave>
            <clave>Fuzzy logic</clave>
            <clave>Temperature control</clave>
            <clave>Temperature sensors</clave>
        </claves>
        <revista>Future Generation Computer Systems</revista>
        <enumeracionRevista>
            <volumenRevista>76</volumenRevista>
        </enumeracionRevista>
        <paginaInicio>275</paginaInicio>
        <paginaFinal>284</paginaFinal>
        <año>2017</año>
    </articulo>
</articulos>